Guide to the General Outdoor Advertising Company Plan Books, 1916-1927
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
General Outdoor Advertising Company Plan Books 1916-1927
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
General Outdoor Advertising Company.
3.0 Linear Feet 200 Items
Billboard and poster company formed in 1925 from the merger of The Fulton Group and Cusack Co.
Outdoor Advertising Plans were scrapbooks that contained examples of billboards and outdoor posters, testimonial correspondence, trade advertisements and other materials. They were organized according to product type. Collection spans the years 1916-1927 and contains 18 scrapbooks. Companies represented include the Poster Advertising Service, General Outdoor, O. J. Gude, the Thomas Cusack Company, General Foods (Maxwell House) and Procter & Gamble (Crisco, Ivory soap). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The General Outdoor Advertising Company Plan Books were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2013.
Collection Overview
Outdoor Advertising Plans were scrapbooks that contained examples of billboards and outdoor posters, testimonial correspondence, trade advertisements and other materials. They were organized according to product type. Collection spans the years 1916-1927 and contains 18 scrapbooks. Companies represented include the Poster Advertising Service, General Outdoor, O. J. Gude, the Thomas Cusack Company, General Foods (Maxwell House) and Procter & Gamble (Crisco, Ivory soap).
Collection Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
General Outdoor Advertising Co
General Foods Corporation
Procter & Gamble Company
Advertising
Advertising -- United States
Advertising -- United States -- History
Advertising, Outdoor
Advertising, Outdoor -- United States
Advertising, Outdoor -- United States -- History
Scrapbooks
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Garrett Orr Papers
Howard Scott Papers
Outdoor Advertising Association of America Archives
Outdoor Advertising Association of America Poster Designs
Strobridge Lithographing Company Advertisements
Detailed Description of Collection
- Outdoor Advertising Plan, 1916-1927 and undated
  - Automobile tires, 1924-1926 (Box 1)
  - Building materials, 1919-1926
  - Competitive (NOAB), 1924-1926
  - Confectionary/Beverages, 1920-1926
  - Drugs and toiletries, 1922-1925
  - Financial institutions, 1916-1924
  - Food (some in Spanish), 1919-1926, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Household utilities including cleansers, 1923-1926
  - Maxwell House, undated
  - Menswear, 1922-1926
  - Merchandising O.D.A., 1926 and undated
  - Miscellaneous, 1921-1926
  - Musical instruments including radio/phonograph, 1922 (Box 3)
  - Office appliances, 1925
  - Procter & Gamble, 1926
  - Publications, printers, stationers, 1919-1926
  - Tobacco, undated
  - Transportation, 1923-1926